We've talked a bit about how neural networks are designed to learn from numerical data.
我们讨论过神经网络如何从数字数据中学习规律
In our case, word embedding is really all about
词嵌入的作用是
improving the ability of networks to learn from texted data.
提高网络从文本数据中学习规律的能力
The idea is this, embeddings can greatly
嵌入通过将数据表示为低维向量
improve the ability of networks to learn from text data,
大大提高了网络
by representing that data as lower-dimensional vectors.
从文本数据中学习规律的能力
Let's think about this in an example.
举个例子
Usually, when you're dealing with text and you split things up into words,
通常在处理文本时 我们会将文本拆分为字词
you tend to have tens of thousands of different words in a large data set.
一个大型数据集包含成千上万的不同字词
When you're using these words as input to a network like an R&amp;N,
在将这些字词当做输入传入 RNN 等网络前
we've seen that we can one-hot encode them.
我们可以独热编码这些字词
What that means is that you have these giant vectors that are like 50,000 units long,
结果生成一个庞大的向量 其中包含约 50,000 个元素
and only one of them is set to one,
只有一个元素设为 1
and all the others are set to zero.
所有其他元素都设为 0
Then, you pass this long vector as input to some hidden layer in the network.
然后将此长向量传入某个隐藏层
The output of this hidden layer is calculated by multiplying
通过将此输入向量乘以某个学习的权重矩阵
that input vector by some matrix of learned weights.
算出隐藏层的输出
The result is a huge matrix of values.
结果是一个庞大的值矩阵
Most of which are zero, because of the initial one-hot vector.
大多数值都为 0 因为初始向量是一个独热向量
So, all these computing resources are used on values that do not hold any information,
计算资源浪费在了很多不包含任何信息的值上
and this is really computationally inefficient.
非常不高效
To solve this problem, we can use embeddings,
为了解决此问题 我们可以使用嵌入
which basically provide a shortcut for doing this matrix multiplication.
它是这种矩阵乘法的便捷方式
To learn word embeddings,
为了学习词嵌入
we use a fully-connected linear layer like you've seen before.
我们使用一个之前见过的全连接线性层级
We'll call this layer the embedding layer,
我们称此层级为嵌入层
and its weights are the embedding weights.
它的权重是嵌入权重
These weights will be values that are learned during training this embedding model,
这些权重将是在训练此嵌入模型过程中学习的值
and they make up a useful weight matrix.
这些值构成了有用的权重矩阵
With this matrix, we can skip the big multiplication step from before,
借助此矩阵 我们可以跳过之前的繁琐乘法步骤
by instead grabbing the values for the output of
直接从权重矩阵中的一行里
our hidden layer directly from a row in our weight matrix.
获取隐藏层的输出值
We can do this because the multiplication of
这是因为
a one-hot encoded vector with a weight matrix,
独热编码向量与权重矩阵相乘
returns only the row of the matrix that corresponds to
仅返回值为 1 或开启的输入单元的索引
the index of the one or the on input unit.
对应的矩阵行
So, instead of doing matrix multiplication,
我们不再进行矩阵乘法运算
we can use the embedding weight matrix as a lookup table.
而是使用嵌入权重矩阵作为查询表
Instead of representing words as one-hot vectors,
并且不再将字词表示为独热向量
we can encode each word as a unique integer.
而是将每个字词编码为唯一整数
As an example, say we have the word heart encoded as the integer 958.
举个例子 假设我们将 heart 表示为整数 958
Then, to get the hidden layer values for heart,
要获取 heart 的隐藏层值
we just take the 958th row of the embedding weight matrix.
我们只需获取嵌入权重矩阵的第 958 行
This process is called an embedding lookup,
这个流程称为嵌入查询
and the number of hidden units is the embedding dimension.
隐藏单元的数量称为嵌入维度
So, the embedding lookup table is just a weight matrix,
嵌入查询表是一个权重矩阵
and the embedding layer is just a hidden layer.
嵌入层是一个隐藏层
It's important to know that the lookup table holds weights that are
注意 就像任何权重矩阵一样
learned during training just like any weight matrix.
查询表存储的是在训练过程中学习的权重
So, this is the basic idea behind how embedding works.
这就是嵌入的基本工作原理
In the next few sections,
在接下来的几个部分
you'll see how word "the vec" uses the embedding layer to find
你将学习 Word2Vec 如何使用嵌入层
vector representations of words that contain semantic meaning.
查找具有语义的字词向量表示法